<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Learn, Practice, Summarize, Share</title>
    <link>https://bsdnet.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Learn, Practice, Summarize, Share</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://bsdnet.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://bsdnet.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 18:51:57 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bsdnet.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Container Stack</title>
      <link>https://bsdnet.github.io/posts/kubernetes-container-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 18:51:57 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bsdnet.github.io/posts/kubernetes-container-stack/</guid>
      <description>In Kubernetes 1.24, dockershim will be removed. What does it mean, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look the container stackbefore and after dockershim removal.
Objective To walkthrough container stack on a Kubernetes node.
Before 1.24 release Since 1.24 release Walk-through Using the opportunity, we can walkthrough the container stack and corresponding tooling on a Kubernetes node from top to bottom.
apiserver apiserver sits on the Kubernetes master, validates and configures data for the api objects which include pods, services, replicationcontrollers and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity Tools</title>
      <link>https://bsdnet.github.io/posts/productivity-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2022 22:00:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bsdnet.github.io/posts/productivity-tools/</guid>
      <description>This post collects productivity tools used in my daily worklife.
Documenting  Excalidraw: Draw a diagram DokuWiki  Programming  Visual Studio Code: Edit code SourceGraph: Search the Github OpenGrok: Search any code, host your own git: Distributed version control system github.com: Well known code repository Review Board: Review Code Gerrit Code Review Jekins: CI/CD tools JIRA: an enterprise bug tracking system Bugzilla: an open source bug tracking system remark: A simple, in-browser, markdown-driven slideshow tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, The Infra Guy</title>
      <link>https://bsdnet.github.io/posts/hello-the-infra-guy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 10:44:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bsdnet.github.io/posts/hello-the-infra-guy/</guid>
      <description>This post describes how I created this blog website using a couple of hours.
Objective The objective is to build a website using Hugo and Github Pages.
Steps Follow the steps listed below:
  Create a Github account if you do not have one
  Create a Github Repository
  Keep in mind, you can&amp;rsquo;t use user name and password to access Git Repo now. You have to use a token a SSH key for the sake of security.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
